<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<modDesc descVersion="105">
    <author>Ritter</author>
    <version>0.8.0.0</version>
    <title>
        <en>Fresh</en>
        <it>Fresco</it>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[
Fresh adds shelf life to your produce and bales - crops age over time and will spoil if not sold or used!

Your harvested crops, processed products, and baled forage now have realistic shelf lives. Fresh vegetables spoil quickly, while canned products last much longer. Bales of grass spoil within days, while silage stays fresh for months. Customize shelf lives via the Fresh Menu!

Fresh Menu (Right Shift+F):
- Inventory Overview: see all perishables with oldest ages
- Loss Statistics: track what you've lost
- Settings: customize shelf lives for any product

Features:
- Supports basegame, DLCs, and maps/mods products
- Configure shelf life for any fillType in Settings
- Configurable warning threshold (6h/12h/24h/48h/72h)
- Age distribution bars (color-coded: blue=fresh, green=good, orange=warning, red=critical)
- Expiring amount and time remaining per fill type
- 100+ products with realistic default shelf lives
- 4 bale types with fermentation handling
- Vehicles, bales, silos, productions, husbandries supported
- Oldest items retrieved first from storage
- Daily loss notifications
- Multiplayer support (server-authoritative)
- Ages saved with your game

Notes:
- Early access - feedback welcome

Documentation: https://github.com/rittermod/FS25_Fresh

Changelog:

0.8.0.0 (Alpha):
- Reworked expiry warnings to use in-game time remaining
- Added configurable warning threshold (6h/12h/24h/48h/72h)
- Improved expiry display - all storage types show amount and time remaining
- Added partial expiry display for vehicles
- Improved time display breakpoints (hours/days/months)

0.7.2.0 (Alpha):
- Added age distribution HUD for bales

0.7.1.0 (Alpha):
- Fixed TMR mixer output tracking - FORAGE amount now correctly tracks all ingredients
- Fixed pig feed (PIGFOOD) losing age when deposited into pigsty
- Fixed containers not aging after enabling expiration for a previously disabled product
- Fixed vehicle showing wrong product freshness after refilling with a product set to 'do not expire'
- Fixed false error log when registering Fresh Menu keybinding in vehicle context

0.7.0.0 (Alpha):
- Added support for ALL fillTypes - basegame, DLCs, and maps/mods now configurable
- Improved Settings sorting - products with types appear first for easier navigation
- Added tooltips in Settings showing fillType details (internal name, type classification)

Full changelog at https://github.com/rittermod/FS25_Fresh
        ]]>        </en>
        <it><![CDATA[
Fresco aggiunge una durata di conservazione ai tuoi prodotti e alle tue balle: i raccolti invecchiano nel tempo e si deteriorano se non venduti o utilizzati!

I tuoi raccolti, i prodotti lavorati e il foraggio imballato ora hanno una durata realistica. Le verdure fresche si deteriorano rapidamente, mentre i prodotti in scatola durano molto più a lungo. Le balle di erba si rovinano in pochi giorni, mentre l'insilato rimane fresco per mesi. Personalizza la durata di conservazione tramite il Fresh Menu!

Fresh Menu (Shift Destro+F):
- Panoramica inventario: visualizza tutti i deperibili con le età più alte
- Statistiche perdite: tieni traccia di ciò che hai perso
- Impostazioni: personalizza la durata di conservazione per qualsiasi prodotto

Funzionalità:
- Supporta prodotti del gioco base, DLC e mappe/mod
- Configura la durata di conservazione per qualsiasi fillType nelle Impostazioni
- Barre di distribuzione dell'età (colori: blu=fresco, verde=buono, arancione=avviso, rosso=critico)
- Oltre 100 prodotti con durate predefinite realistiche
- 4 tipi di balle con gestione della fermentazione
- Supporto per veicoli, balle, sili, produzioni e stalle
- Gli elementi più vecchi vengono prelevati per primi dal magazzino
- Notifiche giornaliere delle perdite
- Supporto multiplayer (server-authoritative)
- Le età vengono salvate nel salvataggio di gioco

Note:
- Accesso anticipato – feedback benvenuto

Documentazione: https://github.com/rittermod/FS25_Fresh

Changelog:

0.7.1.0 (Alpha):
- Corretto il tracciamento dell'output del mixer TMR – la quantità di FORAGGIO ora tiene correttamente conto di tutti gli ingredienti

0.7.0.0 (Alpha):
- Aggiunto supporto per TUTTI i fillType – gioco base, DLC e mappe/mod ora configurabili
- Migliorato l'ordinamento delle Impostazioni – i prodotti con categorie appaiono per primi per una navigazione più semplice
- Aggiunti tooltip nelle Impostazioni che mostrano dettagli del fillType (nome interno, classificazione)

0.6.1.0 (Alpha):
- Corretta la visualizzazione della distribuzione dell'età su veicoli/placeable vuoti (problema di precisione floating point)

0.6.0.0 (Alpha):
- Aggiunta HUD di distribuzione dell'età: barre colorate di freschezza vicino a placeable e veicoli
- Aggiunto interruttore nelle Impostazioni per abilitare/disabilitare la visualizzazione della distribuzione dell'età
- Corretta la visualizzazione della freschezza per fillType
- Corretta la visualizzazione della scadenza solo per fillType deperibili

0.5.0.0 (Early Access):
- Aggiunto Fresh Menu (Shift Destro+F) con inventario, statistiche e impostazioni
- Aggiunte durate di conservazione configurabili per prodotto
- Aggiunto tracciamento delle perdite con notifiche giornaliere
- Migliorata la gestione dei trasferimenti (età dei lotti preservata)
- Ricostruita l'architettura principale per maggiore stabilità

0.4.0.0 (Alpha 5):
- Aggiunto tracciamento dei magazzini placeable (sili, produzioni, stalle)
- Aggiunto tracciamento del cibo nelle stalle
- Aggiunta visualizzazione del conteggio in scadenza per i placeable
- Aggiunta sincronizzazione multiplayer per i magazzini placeable

0.3.0.0 (Alpha 4):
- Aggiunto tracciamento dei veicoli di massa (rimorchi, cisterne, mietitrebbie)
- Esteso dalle pallet a tutti i veicoli con capacità di carico

0.2.0.0 (Alpha 2):
- Aggiunta deperibilità delle balle con 4 tipi di foraggio
- Aggiunto invecchiamento delle balle nei fienili/rimesse
- Aggiunta gestione delle balle in fermentazione

0.1.0.0 (Alpha 1):
- Prima versione alpha
- Aggiunto sistema di prodotti deperibili per 100 tipi di prodotto
- Aggiunto supporto multiplayer e persistenza nei salvataggi
        ]]></it>
    </description>

    <iconFilename>icon_fresh.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>

    <!-- External localization files -->
    <l10n filenamePrefix="languages/l10n"/>

    <!-- Input action: Toggle Fresh menu -->
    <actions>
        <action name="RM_FRESH_MENU"/>
    </actions>

    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="RM_FRESH_MENU">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_rshift KEY_f"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>

    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/main.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>

</modDesc>
